#### Hasan T. Abbas

CONTACT INFORMATION PhD Electrical Engineering Texas A& M University

Department of Electrical & Computer Engineering 212-H WEB Texas A&M University

College Station, TX 77843-3128, USA

Cell: +1-979-422-5347

Fax: +1-979-845-6259

E-mail: hasantahir@tamu.edu Website: hasantahir.github.io

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Placement in an academic position (i.e., faculty, postdoctoral, or research scientist) that allows for advanced research in electromagnetic wave phenomena and plasmonics (i.e., modeling, analysis, design, and verification) with a particular focus on electronic device miniaturization.

#### **EDUCATION**

Texas A& M University, College Station, TX

Ph.D., Electrical and Computer Engineering, August 2012 - August 2017

- Dissertation: Plasmonic Devices in the Terahertz and Optical Frequency do-
- Adviser: Professor Robert D. Nevels
- GPA 4.0
- Area of Study: Numerical Electromagnetics and Plasmonics

University of Engineering & Technology, Lahore, Pakistan

B.Sc., Electrical Engineering, July 2009

- With Honors (absolute marks 76.4%)
- Specialization in Telecommunication and Computer Science

# RESEARCH **INTERESTS**

Electromagnetics, Plasmonics, Numerical Electromagnetics, Miniaturized on-chip Antennas, Nanophotonics, Two-dimensional Physics and materials

**CURRENT** ACADEMIC **APPOINTMENTS**  Fulbright Scholar, Texas A& M University

Department of Electrical & Computer Engineering

• Affiliations:

- Electromagnetics and Microwave Laboratory
- Institute of Quantum Science and Engineering

**Instructor**, Texas A& M University

August 2014 to present

August 2012 to August 2017

- Courses:
  - Electric and Magnetic Fields
  - Applied Electromagnetic Theory

PREVIOUS Lecturer, University of Engineering & Technology, Lahore, Pakistan August 2009 to ACADEMIC August 2012

APPOINTMENTS Department of Electrical Engineering & Technology

- Courses:
  - Electromagnetic Theory
  - Antennas and Wave Propagation
  - Applied Electromagnetics
- Laboratories:
  - Microwave and Antennas Laboratory
  - Communication Systems

BOOK CHAPTERS 2015 Robert D. Nevels, Hasan Tahir Abbas, "Optical Nanoantennas", In Chapter in Handbook of Antenna Technologies, Springer Singapore, pp. 1-33, 2015.

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

H.T., Abbas, X., Zeng, M., AlAmri, R.D., Nevels, M.S., Zubairy, "Nanoscopy using a semiconductor heterostructure as the sample stage", submitted in Optics Express, 2017.

# CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS

- 2017 H.T., Abbas, R.D., Nevels, "An Integral Equation Scheme for Plasma based Thin Sheets", In Antennas and Propagation & USNC/URSI National Radio Science Meeting, 2017 IEEE International Symposium on.
- 2017 H.T., Abbas, R.D., Nevels, K.A., Michalski, "Plasma based Terahertz devices", Wireless & Microwave Circuits & Systems, 2017 IEEE Texas Symposium on.
- 2016 H.T., Abbas, R.D., Nevels, "Plasma based integrated on-chip antenna", In Antennas and Propagation & USNC/URSI National Radio Science Meeting, 2016 IEEE International Symposium on, pp. 1645-1646, 2016.
- 2015 J., Shin, H.T., Abbas, R.D., Nevels, "A numerical method for the electromagnetic field time domain propagator equations", In Antennas and Propagation & USNC/URSI National Radio Science Meeting, 2015 IEEE International Symposium on, pp. 1480-1481, 2015.
- 2015 J., Shin, H.T., Abbas, R.D., Nevels, "A numerical method for the electromagnetic field time domain propagator equations", In Antennas and Propagation & USNC/URSI National Radio Science Meeting, 2015 IEEE International Symposium on, pp. 1480-1481, 2015.
- 2015 H.T., Abbas, J., Shin, R.D., Nevels, "Numerical techniques for evaluating electromagnetic field propagators", In Computational Electromagnetics (ICCEM), 2015 IEEE International Conference on, pp. 22-23, 2015.
- 2014 R.D., Nevels, K.A., Michalski, H.T., Abbas, "Plasmonic and surface wave propagation in boundary layers in the microwave, THz, and optical regimes", In Antenna Measurements & Applications (CAMA), 2014 IEEE Conference on, pp. 1-3, 2014.

# CONFERENCE TALKS

- [1] Complex Plane Interpretation of Nano-Aperture Excited Plasmon Waves. In: *University of Electronic Science and Technology China (UESTC) National Summer School*, Chengdu, China, July, 2015.
- [2] A decomposition and interpretation of plasma and plasmonic waves. In: *Institute* for Quantum Science and Engineering Workshop, College Station, TX, January 13–14, 2015.
- [3] Twisted Waves: Concept and Limitations. In: 2013 IEEE AP-S/USNC-URSI Symposium, Orlando, FL, July 7–13, 2013.

# TEACHING EXPERIENCE

# Texas A&M University, College Station, TX

Substitute Lecturer January 2016

- ECEN 322: Electric and Magnetic Fields
  - Undergraduate course
  - Main instructor: Robert D. Nevels

# Substitute Lecturer

October 2015

- ECEN 445: Applied Electromagnetic Theory
  - Undergraduate course
  - Main instructor: Robert D. Nevels

#### Substitute Lecturer

January 2015

- ECEN 351: Applied Electromagnetics
  - Undergraduate course
  - Main instructor: Robert D. Nevels

# University of Engineering & Technology, KSK Campus, Pakistan

#### Lecturer

August 2009 to August 2012

- Instructor for EE 480: Antennas and Propagation
- Instructor for EE 380: Electromagnetic Theory
- Instructor for EE 381: Applied Electromagnetic Theory

#### Lab In-charge

December 2009 to August 2012

- Set up Microwave and Antennas Laboratory
- Authored Antennas lab manual
- Lab Instructor for EE 360: Communication Systems
  - Spring 2012

#### Honors

#### Fulbright Foreign Student

- Pursue Doctoral Degree at Texas A&M University, 2012–2017 Best Young Faculty
- Department of Electrical Engineering & Technology, UET Lahore, Pakistan, 2010-2011

# PROFESSIONAL

# **Professional Memberships**

- SERVICE
- IEEE Antennas & Propagation Society
- IEEE Microwave Theory & Techniques Society
- American Physical Society

#### Referee Service

- IEEE Antennas and Wireless Propagation Letters
- IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation
- American Journal of Physics

# SOFTWARE AND

**Computer Programming:** 

# HARDWARE SKILLS

• C, C++

Numerical Analysis:

• MATLAB, Python

Desktop Editing and Productivity Software:

- Atom, Git
- TEX (LATEX, BIBTEX, PSTricks),
- Microsoft Office, Google Docs
- TikZ, InkScape

## **Operating Systems:**

• Microsoft Windows family, Linux (Ubuntu)

#### **EXPERTISE**

#### Mathematics:

• PDE, Stability Analysis, Linear Algebra, Fourier Transforms

Embedded and Real-time Systems:

• Software and hardware development with several MCU and DSP platforms (e.g., Atmel ATmega MCU's, Microchip PIC MCU's, Arduino and others)

# STUDENT

### **Usman Samad**

**MENTORING** 

Undergraduate student in Electrical and Computer Engineering, Texas A&M University. Modeling and Implementation of a Home Automation System 2015.

# REFERENCES AVAILABLE TO CONTACT

Furnished upon request.